Guide to the Walter Lowenfels Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1897-1975; Series IV; 0.65; (2 boxes)
  - Photographs of Others and Places, 1930-1971
    - Braymer, Nan, 1971, undated (Box 159, Folder 2723)
    - Douglas, Norman, 1930, undated (Box 159, Folder 2724)
    - Ford, Ford Maddox with Lillian Lowenfels, 1934 (Box 159, Folder 2725)
    - Fraenkel, Michael, 1936, undated (Box 159, Folder 2726)
    - Gover, Robert, undated (Box 159, Folder 2727)
    - Jodorowsky, Raquel, undated (Box 159, Folder 2728)
    - Lally, Michael, 1970 (Box 159, Folder 2729)
    - Mondragon, Sergio with Ximena, Santa and Goyo, 1965 (Box 159, Folder 2730)
    - Rogovin, Milto and Anne, 1973 (Box 159, Folder 2731)
    - Seeger, Pete with Lillian Lowenfels, undated (Box 159, Folder 2732)
    - Shoush, Tawani Wakawa, undated (Box 159, Folder 2733)
    - Siqueiros, David A., 1949-1950 (Box 159, Folder 2734)
    - Stone, Ed, 1969, undated (Box 159, Folder 2735)
    - P___, Jacqueline, 1966 (Box 159, Folder 2736)
    - ____, Ed and Felicity, 1970 March (Box 159, Folder 2737)
    - Unidentified people, 1967-1971, undated (Box 159, Folder 2738)
    - Photographs of
      - Drawing of Walter Lowenfels by Elizabeth Catlett, photographic print, 1954 (Box 159, Folder 2739)
      - Marquis for The Weavers performance, venue unknown, undated (Box 159, Folder 2740)
      - Mays Landing, circa 1965 (Box 159, Folder 2741)
      - Moscow trip, 1964
      - Paintings by David A. Siqueiros, 1949-1950 (Box 159, Folder 2742)
      - Unidentified suspension bridge, undated (Box 159, Folder 2743)
- Other Papers, 1931-1976; Series V; 0.4; (1 box)
  This series contains personal files of Walter Lowenfels, Lillian Lowenfels, and Manna Lowenfels Perpellit, including biographical materials, identification cards, certificates, and financial and estate documents.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Address lists, undated (Box 160, Folder 2744-2745)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 160, Folder 2746)
  - Biographical material, 1939, 1976, undated (Box 160, Folder 2747)
  - Codicil to last will and testament of Walter Lowenfels, 1973 March 2 (Box 160, Folder 2748)
  - Communist Party membership book, 1976 (Box 160, Folder 2749)
  - Diploma of Lillian Lowenfels from University of Pennsylvania, 1947
  - Drawing by "Gynn", 1968 (Box 160, Folder 2750)
  - Drawings by Ernö Metzner for Kameradschaft., undated
  - Drawing by Susan Wald, 1974 (Box 160, Folder 2751)
  - FBI report, 1953 July 30 (Box 160, Folder 2752)
  - Financial papers, including tax returns and estate reports, 1948-1963 (Box 160, Folder 2753)
  - Lists of books by Walter Lowenfels, undated (Box 160, Folder 2754)
  - Literary membership cards, 1973-1976 (Box 160, Folder 2755)
  - Manna's sources, lists of citations, undated (Box 160, Folder 2756-2757)
  - Memorial service programs and poems, 1976 October 9 (Box 160, Folder 2758)
  - Nike Missile Base, Chicago, 1971 (Box 160, Folder 2759)
  - Partial passport and library card of Walter and Lillian Lowenfels, 1931, undated (Box 160, Folder 2760)
  - Rutgers workshop in human relations, 1949-1950 (Box 160, Folder 2761)
  - Smith Act Indictment, 1953 (Box 160, Folder 2761a)
  - University of Pennsylvania placement service application of Lillian Lowenfels, 1945 June 29 (Box 160, Folder 2762)
  - WBAI broadcast of Walter Lowenfels memorial, two cassette tapes, 1976
    Conditions Governing Access
    This material is restricted pending reformatting. Please consult Access Services for more information.
- Printed Material, 1925-1976; Series VI; 4; (10 boxes)
  The series is organized into two subseries: Printed Material about Walter Lowenfels and Other Printed Material.
  Printed Material contains newspapers, magazines, pamphlets, clippings and tearsheets, ephemera, postcards and other printed material collected by Lowenfels. The bulk of the series includes material collected by Lowenfels on a variety of subjects. A small amount of the series consists of articles about Lowenfels.
  - Printed Material about Walter Lowenfels, 1925-1976
    - Alexan, George. "No More Poems of Death, No More Elegies", 1967 (Box 161, Folder 2763)
    - Aragon, Louis. "Love of Peace Is Capable of Breaking Man's Chains", undated (Box 161, Folder 2764)
    - Berger, Art. "Walter Lowenfels - Poet of Survival", undated (Box 161, Folder 2765)
    - Guttman, Allen. "Walter Lowenfels' Poetic Politics", 1965 (Box 161, Folder 2766)
    - Huges, Peter. "Walter Lowenfels - Poet on the Front Lines", 1953 December (Box 161, Folder 2767)
    - Hunter College National Judge-In program, undated (Box 161, Folder 2768)
    - Johnson, Oakley C. "Walter Lowenfels: Poet", 1970 January (Box 161, Folder 2769)
    - Lindemann, Jack. "Love and Death in the Early Poems of Walter Lowenfels, 1922-1929", 1968 (Box 161, Folder 2770)
    - Poetry Society of America Membership List, 1956 (Box 161, Folder 2771)
    - Record of Smith Act Cases, 1956 October 1 (Box 161, Folder 2772)
    - "Shall Freedom of Speech Apply to All Americans?", circa 1955 (Box 161, Folder 2773)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert, undated (Box 161, Folder 2774)
    - Ephemera, 1954-1976, undated (Box 161, Folder 2775)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1925-1976, undated (Box 161, Folder 2776-2782)
    - Blank stationery, undated (Box 161, Folder 2783)
  - Other Printed Material, 1927-1976
    - Academic Freedom: some recent Philadelphia episodes. American Civil Liberties Union, Philadelphia Branch, undated (Box 162, Folder 2784)
    - Afro-American Affairs, 1970 November 17
    - Agency of Man on Earth. Carol O. Sauer, 1956 (Box 162, Folder 2785)
    - Akwesasne Notes, 1971 December
    - Alternative Perspectives on Vietnam, 1965 July (Box 162, Folder 2786)
    - The American Book Collector, 1961 May (Box 162, Folder 2787)
    - American Dialog, 1969 (Box 162, Folder 2788)
    - American Report, 1971 March 19
    - American Scientist, 1945 January (Box 162, Folder 2789)
    - Américas, 1965 July (Box 162, Folder 2790)
    - "Appeals to the Governor of California to Save the Life of Wesley Robert Wells", 1954 February 10 (Box 162, Folder 2791)
    - "Authors Guild Bulletin", 1973 (Box 162, Folder 2792)
    - Berkeley: A Journal of Modern Culture, undated
    - Betrayal, 1964 (Box 162, Folder 2793)
    - Black News, 1970 March
    - The Bond, 1970 January 15
    - Book Week, 1964 November 8
    - Broadside, 1965-1970 (Box 162, Folder 2794-2797)
    - "Can Americans Tolerate Prison for Ideas?", 1954 April (Box 162, Folder 2798)
    - The Canadian Forum, 1968 April (Box 162, Folder 2799)
    - Catalog, 1968 (Box 162, Folder 2800)
    - The Catholic Radical, 1968 October 4
    - Catholic Worker, 1969 February
    - César Vallejo: Vida y Obra. Hispanic Insititute in the United States, 1952 (Box 162, Folder 2801)
    - Civil Liberties, 1956 May (Box 162, Folder 2802)
    - Civil Rights Publication, 1955 May (Box 162, Folder 2803)
    - Congressional Record, 1965 July 16 (Box 162, Folder 2804)
    - Connections, 1972 (Box 162, Folder 2805)
    - "The Crossing Press", 1972 (Box 162, Folder 2806)
    - The Crusader, 1952 May 31
    - "The Cultural Congress of Havana", 1968 January 4-11 (Box 162, Folder 2807)
    - Daily Worker, 1973 November 23
    - "Dangerous Anti-Peace Policy in the German Federal Republic", 1963 (Box 163, Folder 2808)
    - Demokratia, 1969-1970 (Box 163, Folder 2809-2810)
    - "District and County Reports", 1951 May 7 (Box 163, Folder 2811)
    - D'Masta Morir Tot És Vida, circa 1970 (Box 163, Folder 2812)
    - "Eat Me! Drink Me!" Psalms, 1960 (Box 163, Folder 2813)
    - "Eighth Anniversary at the Franklin Institute", 1947 April 28 (Box 163, Folder 2814)
    - El Grito, 1973 April
    - Epos, 1967 (Box 163, Folder 2815)
    - "Facts and Opinions, McCarran Internal Security Act", undated (Box 163, Folder 2816)
    - "The Frame-up of Benjamin Lowell Careathers", 1953 (Box 163, Folder 2817)
    - France Nouvelle, 1974 November
    - Freedomways, 1966-1968 (Box 163, Folder 2818-2821)
    - Guajana, 1967 July (Box 163, Folder 2822)
    - "Hampshire Poets", undated (Box 163, Folder 2823)
    - Here and Now, 1967 (Box 163, Folder 2824)
    - I.F. Stone's Bi-Weekly, 1965 November 16 (Box 163, Folder 2825)
    - "In Defense of the People's Black & White History and Culture", undated (Box 163, Folder 2826)
    - The Indian in American History, 1969 -1971 (Box 163, Folder 2827-2828)
    - "Information Bulletin Issued by World Marxist Review Publishers", 1965 March 18 (Box 163, Folder 2829)
    - Information International, 1968
    - "The International Henry Miller Letter", 1961 June (Box 163, Folder 2830)
    - Internationalism and Nationalism. Lin Shao-Chi, undated (Box 163, Folder 2831)
    - Interracial Books for Children, 1971-1972
    - IVE News, 1957 April 17
    - Jewish Currents, 1967 June (Box 164, Folder 2832)
    - Kauri 31, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 2833)
    - Kelsie, 1968 (Box 164, Folder 2834)
    - The Ladder, 1972 (Box 164, Folder 2835)
    - Land and Sun, 1970 (Box 164, Folder 2836)
    - Les Lettres Françaises, 1953-1971, undated
    - Letters from Prison. Martin Sostre, 1969 May (Box 164, Folder 2837)
    - Liberator, 1970 July (Box 164, Folder 2838)
    - Love Raps, 1969 (Box 164, Folder 2839)
    - McCarthyism in the Courts, 1953 (Box 164, Folder 2840)
    - Malaquias Montoya, undated (Box 164, Folder 2841)
    - "Martin Sostre: Report From Prison, Affidavit", 1972
    - Marxism and Modern Literature. Gaylord C. Leroy, 1967 (Box 164, Folder 2842)
    - Mass Psychology of Facism, preface. Wilhelm Reich, undated (Box 164, Folder 2843)
    - The Militant, 1973 October 19
    - The Nation, 1956-1969 (Box 164, Folder 2844-2848)
    - National Guardian, 1968 January 20
    - National Parks & Conservation Magazine, 1970 May (Box 164, Folder 2849)
    - The Negro People in the Struggle for Peace and Freedom. Benjamin J. Dans, 1951 February (Box 164, Folder 2850)
    - New American and Canadian Poetry, 1972 (Box 164, Folder 2851)
    - New Foundations, 1953 (Box 164, Folder 2852)
    - The New Republic, 1967-1968 (Box 164, Folder 2853-2854)
    - New Times, 1950-1974 (Box 164, Folder 2855-2861)
    - Nickel Review, 1970
    - Not Guilty: the Case of Claude Lightfoot, 1955 June (Box 164, Folder 2862)
    - OzyMandias, 1965 September (Box 164, Folder 2863)
    - Party Affairs, 1971 November (Box 165, Folder 2864)
    - Party Vigilance Against Enemy Infiltration, 1953 Februrary (Box 165, Folder 2865)
    - Peacemaker, 1965-1966 (Box 165, Folder 2866)
    - The People, the Press, and Seven Seas Books, undated (Box 165, Folder 2867)
    - People's China Stands for Peace, 1950 November 28 (Box 165, Folder 2868)
    - People's World, 1957 October 12
    - Philosophy and Phenomenological Research, 1962 December (Box 165, Folder 2869)
    - [Photographs by Rewi Alley], undated (Box 165, Folder 2870)
    - The Poetic Tradition, 1968 (Box 165, Folder 2871)
    - The Poetry Center, 1964 (Box 165, Folder 2872)
    - Poetry Public, 1955 July (Box 165, Folder 2873)
    - The Poet's Mission, 1963 (Box 165, Folder 2874)
    - Political Affairs, 1963-1973 (Box 165, Folder 2875-2878)
    - A Political Biography of Angela Davis, undated (Box 165, Folder 2879)
    - The Providence Review, 1973 (Box 165, Folder 2880)
    - Publisher's Weekly, 1971 March 15 (Box 165, Folder 2881)
    - Quarry, 1971 (Box 165, Folder 2882)
    - Quetzal, 1971 (Box 165, Folder 2883)
    - Radical America, 1970 August (Box 165, Folder 2884)
    - Ritual: A Book of Primitive Rites and Events. Jerome Rothenberg, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 2885)
    - The Role of Right Social Democracy, undated (Box 165, Folder 2886)
    - The San Francisco Book Review, 1972 (Box 165, Folder 2887)
    - Sansculottes, undated (Box 165, Folder 2888)
    - "Science and Peace," Nobel Lecture by Linus Pauling, 1964 (Box 165, Folder 2889)
    - Science Fiction. Willard Bain, 1967 (Box 165, Folder 2890)
    - Scientific American, 1950, 1966 (Box 166, Folder 2891-2892)
    - The Silence of the Good People, 1962 September (Box 166, Folder 2893)
    - Sing Out, 1951-1971 (Box 166, Folder 2894-2897)
    - Some Air Conditioned Poems, undated (Box 166, Folder 2898)
    - "Southern Christian Leadership Conference", 1963 March (Box 166, Folder 2899)
    - The Southern Patriot, 1964-1969 (Box 166, Folder 2900-2902)
    - Soviet Highlights, 1959 August (Box 166, Folder 2903)
    - Soviet Russia Today, 1951 January (Box 166, Folder 2904)
    - Science and Peace, 1964 January (Box 166, Folder 2905)
    - A Sunday in Central Park, 1969 September (Box 166, Folder 2906)
    - Syracuse Poems, 1968 (Box 166, Folder 2907)
    - This Is My Husband. Esther Jackson, undated (Box 166, Folder 2908)
    - "Times Change Press", 1972 (Box 166, Folder 2909)
    - "Unicorn Catalogue", 1967-1968 (Box 166, Folder 2910)
    - USSR Information Bulletin, 1951 January 12 (Box 166, Folder 2911)
    - Vallejo y su tierra. Francisco Jaquierdo Rios, undated (Box 166, Folder 2912)
    - The Vindicator, 1971 November 19
    - Voices for Freedom, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 2913-2914)
    - Voks Bulletin, undated (Box 166, Folder 2915)
    - A Walk in Alabama. Guy Endore, 1965 April 6 (Box 166, Folder 2916)
    - Way Catholic Viewpoints, 1967 April (Box 166, Folder 2917)
    - Wilderness Report, 1969 September 15 (Box 166, Folder 2918)
    - Win Magazine, 1970 May 1 (Box 166, Folder 2919)
    - Women's Songbook, 1971 (Box 166, Folder 2920)
    - World Marxist Review, 1969-1970 (Box 166, Folder 2921-2922)
    - Unidentified printed materials, undated (Box 166, Folder 2923-2926)
    - Untitled print by Anton Refreiger, undated
    - Ephemera, 1948-1966 (Box 167, Folder 2927-2942)
    - Ephemera, 1967-1975 (Box 168, Folder 2943-2951)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 169, Folder 2952-2955)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1927-1974, undated (Box 170, Folder 2956-2965)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 170, Folder 2966)
    - Scrapbook containing pages and clippings from The Daily Worker and other clippings, circa 1951-1954
      This item is restricted due to its fragile nature. Please consult curator for access.
    - Scrapbook containing loose clippings and printed material of reviews on Lowenfels's work (Series VI), 1960-1961
- Oversize, 1946-1975; 1; (10 boxes)
  - Guthrie, Woody (Series I), circa 1954 (Box 171, Folder 2967)
  - "American Voices," proofs (Series II), circa 1953 (Box 172, Folder 2968-2971)
  - "An Artist Looks at the New Europe," newspaper clipping from The Worker, 1948 January 18 (Box 172, Folder 2972)
  - "The Ballad for Un-American Blues," with Lee Hays and Waldemar Hille (Series II), 1947 (Box 171, Folder 2973)
  - "Billionaires with Bombs," The Worker (Series II), 1946 August 25 (Box 171, Folder 2974)
  - "Constitution Day, 1951," The Worker (Series II), 1951 September 15 (Box 171, Folder 2975)
  - "Earth Shall Smile," lyrics by Walter Lowenfels, music by Waldemar Hille (Series II), undated (Box 171, Folder 2976)
  - "Epithalium," broadside (Series II), undated (Box 171, Folder 2977)
  - "For the Freedom of Morton Sobell," with Waldemar Hille (Series II), undated (Box 171, Folder 2978)
  - Found poems, printed material (Series II), 1972-1975 (Box 171, Folder 2979)
  - "The Heiress Never Met the Miner," from The New Yorker (Series II), 1948 (Box 171, Folder 2980)
  - "Is There Not a Cause," with Karol Fahnestock (Series II), 1960 March 23 (Box 171, Folder 2981)
  - Poesie et Revolutions, French translation by Francois Hugot, galley proofs (Series II), undated (Box 172, Folder 2982)
  - "The Prisoners," proofs (Series II), circa 1954 (Box 172, Folder 2982a)
  - "A Steelworker Rates the Financial Page," The Worker (Series II), 1949 (Box 172, Folder 2983)
  - Walt Whitman's Civil War, galley proofs (Series II), 1960 (Box 172, Folder 2984-2985)
  - Walt Whitman's Civil War, galley proofs (Series II), 1960 (Box 173, Folder 2986-2988)
  - Who Is Lenin? Americans Respond, printed material (Series II), 1970 (Box 171, Folder 2989)
  - Baraka, Imamu Amiri and Larry Neal. Black Fire. Galley proofs (Series III), circa 1968 (Box 174, Folder 2990)
  - Chandra, G. S. Sharat. "Bangla(waterpipe)Desh" (Series III), 1974 June (Box 174, Folder 2991)
  - Harmon, William. Wesleyan, galley proof (Series III), 1971 (Box 174, Folder 2992)
  - Vallejo, Cesar. Translations by Nan Braymer and Lillian Lowenfels (Series III), undated (Box 174, Folder 2993)
  - Lowenfels, Walter (Series IV), 1957, undated (Box 171, Folder 2994)
  - Moscow trip photographs (Series IV), 1964 (Box 171, Folder 2995)
  - Diploma of Lillian Lowenfels from University of Pennsylvania (Series V), 1947 (Box 171, Folder 2996)
  - Drawings by Ernö Metzner for Kameradschaft. (Series V), undated (Box 175, Folder 2997-2998)
  - Afro-American Affairs (Series VI), 1970 November 17 (Box 176, Folder 2999)
  - Akwesasne Notes (Series VI), 1971 December (Box 176, Folder 3000)
  - American Report (Series VI), 1971 March 19 (Box 176, Folder 3001)
  - Berkeley: A Journal of Modern Culture (Series VI), undated (Box 176, Folder 3002)
  - Black News (Series VI), 1970 March (Box 176, Folder 3003)
  - The Bond (Series VI), 1970 January 15 (Box 176, Folder 3004)
  - Book Week (Series VI), 1964 November 8 (Box 176, Folder 3005)
  - The Catholic Radical (Series VI), 1968 October 4 (Box 176, Folder 3006)
  - Catholic Worker (Series VI), 1969 February (Box 176, Folder 3007)
  - The Crusader (Series VI), 1952 May 31 (Box 176, Folder 3008)
  - Daily Worker (Series VI), 1973 November 23 (Box 176, Folder 3009)
  - El Grito (Series VI), 1973 April (Box 176, Folder 3010)
  - France Nouvelle (Series VI), 1974 November (Box 176, Folder 3011)
  - Information International (Series VI), 1968 (Box 176, Folder 3012)
  - Interracial Books for Children (Series VI), 1971-1972 (Box 176, Folder 3013-3015)
  - IVE News (Series VI), 1957 April 17 (Box 176, Folder 3016)
  - Les Lettres Françaises (Series VI), 1953-1971, undated (Box 177, Folder 3017-3026)
  - Martin Sostre: Report From Prison, Affidavit (Series VI), 1972 (Box 177, Folder 3027)
  - The Militant (Series VI), 1973 October 19 (Box 177, Folder 3028)
  - National Guardian (Series VI), 1968 January 20 (Box 178, Folder 3029)
  - Nickel Review (Series VI), 1970 (Box 178, Folder 3030-3031)
  - People's World (Series VI), 1957 October 12 (Box 178, Folder 3032)
  - The Vindicator (Series VI), 1971 November 19 (Box 178, Folder 3033)
  - Untitled print by Anton Refreiger (Series VI), undated (Box 179, Folder 3034)
  - Ephemera (Series VI), 1968 (Box 179, Folder 3035)
  - Newspaper clippings (Series VI), 1927-1975, undated (Box 179, Folder 3036-3042)
  - Scrapbook containing loose clippings and other materials, mostly reviews of works by Lowenfels, 1960-1961 (Box 180, Folder 3043-3046)
- Restricted Fragile Materials, 1920s-1970s; 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Series I, undated (Box 181, Folder 3047)
  - Series V, 1976 (Box 181, Folder 3048-3049)
  - Series VI, 1920s-1970s, undated (Box 181, Folder 3050-3052)
- Restricted Fragile Materials Oversize, 1920s-1970s; 0.25; (2 boxes)
  - Series II, undated (Box 182, Folder 3053)
  - Series VI, 1920s-1970s, undated (Box 182, Folder 3054-3057)
  - Series VI, 1951-1954 (Box 183, Folder 3058)